## Lloyd Mills 541.420.5961

# 1714 NW Couch #12 Portland Oregon, 97209 541 420 5961 millsl@engr.oregonstate.edu

## **Objective**

To use my knowledge of the energy production processes and safety system analysis to benefit the company. To use my specialized knowledge in design, construction, research, and development of generation stations and facilitates from an efficiency and safety perspective.

## **Professional Achievements**

## Research and development

#### Scholastic

3.24 GPA as a Professional Nuclear Engineering Student

Worked with a team of fellow engineering student to developed numerical and analytical mathematical concept of optimizing solar radiation collection using only recycled parts available to a third world countries.

Helped in the design and optimization of High Temperature Gas Reactor Test Facility under the guidance of an Associate Professor.

Mathematically constructed with a team of fellow engineering students an optimal wooden beam designed to withstand certain stress and strain analysis.

#### **Employment**

Able to get and maintain steady client base, bringing in the company minimum of \$6000 revenue monthly with sales of training, supplements, membership, and customer services

Promoted to Training Manager with responsibility for other co-workers

Twice recipient of Employee of the month acknowledgement for outstanding Customer Service

## **Skills**

Nuclear Reactor operation class and Operations Process. Fuel efficiencies with emphasis on Thermodynamics, Heat Transfer, Power Calibrations, and Thermal Hydraulic Safety System Analysis.

Radiation Detection and Dosimetry classes with lab and theory, Special interest in Thermal Hydraulics and reactor safety analysis

Communication, able to write and present in formal setting as well as team synergy promotion

Proficient in CAD, Solid Works and numerical programs such as MCNP, RELAP, and MATLAB

Familiar with financial planning and spread sheets, able create budgets with multiple variables in order to insure efficiency and effectiveness cost benefit analysis.

## **Work History**

Oregon State University:Nuclear Engineering Tutor2011-PresentElite Fitness and Education:Personal Trainer2009-2011Central Oregon Community College:Math, Engineering, Physics Tutor2008-2011Albertsons Grocery:Cashier, Courtesy Clerk2008-2009

### **Education**

Oregon State University Major: Nuclear Engineering Sept 2011 - Present

Bachelors of Science 2013

Central Oregon Community College Major: Pre-Engineering/General Sept 2008- June 2011

Associate of Arts Oregon Transfer